<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ECON 100 on Mohammad Zafar&#39;s University Notes</title>
    <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ECON 100 on Mohammad Zafar&#39;s University Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4: Demand</title>
      <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 17:44:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-4/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: I left out the last part of today&amp;rsquo;s lecture (Beginning of Demand Curve Shifts) because it&amp;rsquo;s more cohesive to sum it up with the next lecture.
Summary Individual Demand Takeaways Individual Demand Curve plots quantity a person plans to buy at each price
 Keep other factors constant (ceteris paribus)  Law of Demand states as prices fall, quantity rises
Your Demand Curve Takeaways Rational Rule for Buyer: Buy more if MB &amp;gt;= Price</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3: Four Core Principles pt.2</title>
      <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 20:00:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-3/</guid>
      <description>Summary Opportunity Cost Takeaways  Opportunity Cost is the most valuable alternative you give up to pursue said choice Every choice has opportunity cost, even non-monetary choices Ignore sunk costs PPF is used to visualize opportunity cost Scarcity creates limitations and opportunity cost  Marginal Principle Takeaways The marginal principle tells you to break “how many” decisions into a series of smaller, marginal decisions.
 If the marginal benefit exceeds the marginal cost, then buy that additional unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2: What is Economics? &#43; Four Core Principles</title>
      <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 22:21:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-2/</guid>
      <description>Summary  Economics gives you a toolkit to study choices and solve problems There are Four Core Principles that govern the choices made in economics Cost Benefit Principle: Using costs + benefits to shape decisions Willingness to Pay is a way to convert nonfinancial costs to monetary benefit Economic Surplus is when the benefits exceed the cost of a choice Good economists avoid Framing techniques Opportunity Cost Principle: The true cost of something is the next best alternative you have to give up to get it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 22:20:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-1/</guid>
      <description>Summary  We reviewed the syllabus You must the textbook + online platform. (just buy the online platform for $123)  Also make an iClicker account, is free with the learning platform   You HAVE to get 40% MINIMUM on the Final Exam  Main Stuff  ECON 100, or Introduction to Economic Issues, is focused on using basic economic concepts to explore economic issues like unemployment, climate change, inflation, healthcare, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
