<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ECON 100 on Mohammad Zafar&#39;s University Notes</title>
    <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ECON 100 on Mohammad Zafar&#39;s University Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2: What is Economics? &#43; Four Core Principles</title>
      <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 22:21:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-2/</guid>
      <description>Summary  Economics gives you a toolkit to study choices and solve problems  What is Economics? Economics is simply the study of choices.
 It uses rational and analytic thinking along with scientific techniques to analyse choices across a variety of topics The study of Economics gives you a toolkit to approaching, understanding, and solving problems  Four Core Principles of Economics Although Economics is a vast field that encompassed all sorts of decision analysis and problem solving, it is often encompassed into Four Core Principles</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 22:20:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://school.mohammadzafar.com/w2024/econ-100/lecture-1/</guid>
      <description>Summary  We reviewed the syllabus You must the textbook + online platform. (just buy the online platform for $123)  Also make an iClicker account, is free with the learning platform   You HAVE to get 40% MINIMUM on the Final Exam  Main Stuff  ECON 100, or Introduction to Economic Issues, is focused on using basic economic concepts to explore economic issues like unemployment, climate change, inflation, healthcare, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
